Adam Bohling | Software Engineer

Centennial, CO 80122 | (608) 217-1130 | abohling011@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/n/adambohling/

Summary

I'm a full stack web developer with a background in sales and management. Since graduating from Springboard's Full Stack Engineering program, I have worked with private companies building websites and SEOs. I have focused on building and testing applications using React, JS, Redux, Python, and SQL. I have used my problem-solving and collaborative skills on challenging projects, and I am motivated to continue my learning as a software developer.

Technical Skills

Languages: CSS, HTML5, JavaScript, Python, and SQL

Libraries and Frameworks: Git, Ajax, jQuery, Flask, PostgreSQL, NodeJS, Express, React, Redux, Jest, Jasmine, SQLAlchemy, and WordPress

Skills: WordPress, Agile Methodologies, Computer Science Fundamentals, Problem Solving, Data Analysis, DOM Manipulation, Web Development, Data Structures, and Event-Driven Programming

Projects

Elevated Finance - https://github.com/abohling/stock-picker

- A Stock analyzing app which performs calls to Yahoo Fiance's API and displays the data and other financial information into comprehensive graphs. The app uses Python, Flask, and SQLAlchemy on the backend and JavaScript, CSS, html5, ChartJS, and Bootstrap on the frontend. Savable accounts, allow users to save and review favorited stocks with live data.

Elevated Fitness Website - https://github.com/abohling/Elevated-Fitness

-A company website that allows customizable payment to allocate funds to various accounts. The website uses NodeJS, SQL, and Express on the backend and React and JavaScript on the frontend. Savable accounts, allow users to make payments using the Strip-API.

Work Experience

Springboard Full Stack Software Engineering Career Track - March 2022 - May 2023

- Frontend Development- Worked with Python, JS, React, and Jquery. Projects included building messaging boards, remaking a Twitter clone, and creating a Jeopardy game
- Backend Development Worked with Express, Flask, SQL, and Postgres to build databases, APIs, data structures, and different algorithms. Projects included making a song library and foreign exchange converter.

Elevated Fitness Solutions, Centennial - Owner - November 2021 - PRESENT

- Utilize a self-designed booking website using the technologies ReactJS, NodeJS, and Express, Strip API.
- Execute day-to-day business operations including bookkeeping, scheduling, training, and customer service.
- Consult with +30 customers weekly by assessing personal needs to create short-term achievable goals.

Anytime Fitness, Denver— *Area Manager* – June 2016 – June 2018

- Oversaw day-to-day operations for multiple locations with an \$80k monthly review.
- Created and defined the organizational structure for the area, including trainers, managers, sales teams, and office personnel.
- Exceeded sale and review targets by 48% for two consecutive years.

Education

Springboard, Remote - Full Stack Software Engineering - March 2021 - April 2022

Madison College, Madison, WI - Associates of Arts - August 2012 - May 2014